<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<command
	xmlns:fx="http://javafx.com/fxml"
	 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	 >
  	<description>Combine variant records from different sources</description>
  	<libraries>
  		<library href="gatkjfx.jar" main="true"/>
  	</libraries>
  	<options>
  		<xi:include href="mod.common.xml" parse="xml"  xpointer="xpointer(/options/node())"/>
  		
		<com.github.lindenb.jvarkit.jfx.components.FilesChooserPane
	     	 	fx:id="inputvcfs"
	     	 	filter="Variants Files: vcf vcf.gz bcf list"
	     	 	saveKey="picard.in"
	     	 	required="true"
	     	 	label="The INPUT VCF or BCF file"
	     	 	description="The INPUT VCF or BCF file"
	     	 	 minCardinality="1"
	     	 	/>
     	 <com.github.lindenb.jvarkit.jfx.components.FileChooserPane
     	 	fx:id="outputvcf"
     	 	filter="Variants Files: vcf vcf.gz bcf"
     	 	saveKey="picard.out"
     	 	required="true"
     	 	open="false"
     	 	label="The OUTPUT VCF or BCF file"
     	 	description="The OUTPUT VCF or BCF file"
     	 	/> 	
     	 	
     	<ComboBox fx:id="genotypeMergeOptions">
     		<label> Determines how we should merge genotype records for samples shared across the ROD files</label>
     		 <options>
	     		 <option value="UNIQUIFY">Make all sample genotypes unique by file. Each sample shared across RODs gets named sample.ROD.</option>
	     		 <option value="PRIORITIZE">Take genotypes in priority order (see the priority argument).</option>
	     		 <option value="UNSORTED"> Take the genotypes in any order.</option>
	     		 <option value="REQUIRE_UNIQUE">Require that all samples/genotypes be unique between all inputs</option>
     		</options>
     	</ComboBox>
     	
        <ComboBox fx:id="filteredRecordsMergeType">
     		<label> Determines how we should handle records seen at the same site in the VCF, but with different FILTER fields</label>
     		 <options>
	     		 <option value="KEEP_IF_ANY_UNFILTERED" selected="true">Union - leaves the record if any record is unfiltered</option>
	     		 <option value="KEEP_IF_ALL_UNFILTERED">Requires all records present at site to be unfiltered. VCF files that don't contain the record don't influence this</option>
	     		 <option value="KEEP_UNCONDITIONAL" >If any record is present at this site (regardless of possibly being filtered), then all such records are kept and the filters are reset.</option>
     		</options>
     	</ComboBox>
     	  	
  <CheckBox fx:id="assumeIdenticalSamples" selected="false">
    <label>Assume input VCFs have identical sample sets and disjoint calls</label>
    <description>This option allows you to perform a simple merge (concatenation) to combine the VCFs, drastically reducing runtime. Note that in many cases where you think you want to use this option, you may want to check out the CatVariants tool instead, because CatVariants provides the same functionality, but does so even more efficiently.</description>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="excludeNonVariants" selected="false">
    <label>Exclude sites where no variation is present after merging</label>
    <description>Exclude sites that do not contain any called ALT alleles in the merged callset. The evaluation is made after the merging procedure is complete.</description>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="filteredAreUncalled" selected="false">
    <label>Treat filtered variants as uncalled</label>
    <description>If enabled, this flag causes filtered variants (i.e. variant records where the FILTER field is populated by something other than PASS or a dot) to be omitted from the output.</description>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="mergeInfoWithMaxAC" selected="false">
    <label>Use the INFO content of the record with the highest AC</label>
    <description>By default, the INFO field of the merged variant record only contains the INFO field attributes for which all original overlapping records had the same values. Discordant attributes are therefore discarded. This flag allows you to override that behavior and simply copy over the INFO field contents of whichever record had the highest AC value.</description>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="minimalVCF" selected="false">
    <label>Emit a sites-only file</label>
    <description>If this flag is enabled, the INFO, FORMAT and sample-level (genotype) fields will not be emitted to the output file.</description>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="printComplexMerges" selected="false">
    <label>Emit interesting sites requiring complex compatibility merging to file</label>
  </CheckBox>
  <CheckBox fx:id="suppressCommandLineHeader" selected="false">
    <label>Do not output the command line to the header</label>
    <description>By default, this tool writes the command line that was used in the header of the output VCF file. This flag enables you to override that behavior . This is most often useful when combining variants for dozens or hundreds of smaller VCFs iteratively, to avoid cluttering the header with a lot of command lines.</description>
  </CheckBox>

  <Spinner fx:id="minimumN" >
    <label>Minimum number of input files the site must be observed in to be included</label>
    <description>Sites that are present in fewer than this number of inputs will be ignored. This is a convenient way to build a collection of common variants and exclude rare variants.</description>
    <valueFactory>
      <SpinnerValueFactory.IntegerSpinnerValueFactory min="0" initialValue="1">
        <max>
          <java.lang.Integer fx:constant="MAX_VALUE"/>
        </max>
      </SpinnerValueFactory.IntegerSpinnerValueFactory>
    </valueFactory>
  </Spinner>

  <TextField text="set" fx:id="setKey">
    <label>Key name for the set attribute</label>
    <description>Key used in the INFO key value tag emitted describing which set(s) the combined record came from (e.g. set control). This provides the option to override the default naming, so instead of set control you could have it be origin control, or any other word you want that is not already an INFO field attribute. Set this to 0027null0027 if you don0027t want the set attribute emitted at all.</description>
  </TextField>

     	
     	
	</options>
</command>
